(competition in life)
(인생에서의 경쟁)
(The characters, events, groups, organizations and backgrounds of this drama are purely fictitious. We hereby inform you that)
(본 드라마에 등장하는 인물, 사건, 단체, 조직, 배경 등은 순전히 허구입니다. 이를 알려드립니다.)
Who is Park Yun-soo?
박윤수는 누구인가?
( Executive Director Zheng Souhuan, Director of Business Department Marketing Group )
( 전무이사 Zheng Souhuan, 사업부 마케팅 그룹 이사 )
Park Yoon-jo from the Public Relations Team 3 wrote this report
본 보고서는 홍보3팀 박윤조 님이 작성하였습니다.
Who is she?
그녀는 누구입니까?
Chief, please calm down first.
과장님, 먼저 진정하세요.
Hello, Chi Yinzhen
안녕하세요, Chi Yinzhen 님
Is this how you manage your team members?
팀원 관리는 이렇게 하시나요?
Is marketing the problem for Cerdix's sluggish sales ?
Cerdix의 판매 부진이 마케팅 문제인가요 ?
Why does the report mention marketing concepts?
보고서에서 마케팅 개념을 언급하는 이유는 무엇입니까?
And how dare you write such a report and submit it to a senior executive meeting?
그런데 어떻게 감히 그런 보고서를 작성하여 고위 간부 회의에 제출합니까?
I just came back from a business trip and attended a senior executive meeting
방금 출장에서 돌아와 고위 간부 회의에 참석했습니다.
And Serdix is ​​the first bill!
그리고 Serdix가 첫 번째 청구서입니다!
Did you know that this was a project that I oversaw from the ground up?
이 프로젝트가 제가 처음부터 직접 감독한 프로젝트라는 것을 알고 계셨나요?
Are you deliberately trying to trouble me?
일부러 나를 괴롭히려는 거야?
Nako, Chief
나개, 실장
That report is not about marketing ideas...
그 보고서는 마케팅 아이디어에 관한 것이 아닙니다...
Who are you?
누구세요?
I'm Park Yoon-so
저는 박윤소입니다
Are you Park Yun-soo?
박윤수입니까?
Chief
실장
Why are you writing this kind of report?
왜 이런 보고서를 쓰나요?
People in the public relations team just do public relations without your analysis!
홍보팀 사람들은 분석도 없이 그냥 홍보만 하는군요!
Chief
실장
I think digital PR is the department closest to consumers
디지털PR은 소비자와 가장 가까운 부서라고 생각해요
So of course we have to analyze the results…
그러니 당연히 결과를 분석해야 합니다…
Really
정말
(This event is also known as the Zheng Shouhuan Victory of Serdix)
(이 이벤트는 Serdix의 Zheng Shouhuan 승리 라고도 알려져 있습니다 .)
(A few days before Zheng Shouhuan's great victory in Serdix )
(정수환이 세르딕스에서 대승을 거두기 며칠 전 )
(Episode 7)
(7화)
Please come in
오세요
represent
대표하다
Masaaki
允昭
Are you occupied?
바쁘신가요?
According to the offline activity data,
오프라인 활동 데이터에 따르면,
Questionnaires and responses were unsatisfactory
설문지와 응답이 만족스럽지 못했습니다.
Social media promotion is almost ineffective
소셜 미디어 홍보는 거의 효과가 없습니다
So I looked at the initial sales after launch
그래서 출시 후 초기 판매량을 살펴보니
It's just terrible
정말 끔찍해요
I don’t think there’s a big problem with the event itself
행사 자체에는 큰 문제가 없다고 생각합니다
We have ongoing internal meetings
내부회의를 지속적으로 진행하고 있습니다
Change and adjust creative marketing techniques and media strategies
창의적인 마케팅 기법과 미디어 전략을 변경하고 조정합니다.
This is the first time a key performance indicator has not been met
핵심성과지표(KPI)가 충족되지 않은 것은 이번이 처음이다.
So why is this event...
그럼 이 이벤트는 왜...?
The problem really lies in the product, right?
문제는 정말 제품에 있습니다. 그렇죠?
In fact, within our company
실제로 우리 회사 내에서는
The Serdix branding was proposed early in the preparation of the proposal
Serdix 브랜딩은 제안 준비 초기에 제안되었습니다.
there are many problems
문제가 많다
Not only the packaging design but also the emphasized product functions are problematic.
포장 디자인뿐만 아니라 제품 기능을 강조한 부분도 문제다.
So is it really necessary to change the brand identity?
그렇다면 브랜드 아이덴티티를 바꾸는 것이 꼭 필요한가?
(Brand Identity: Brand Image Integration)
(브랜드 아이덴티티: 브랜드 이미지 통합)
Is it too late to replace it now?
지금 교체하기에는 너무 늦었나요?
Even a small business needs to change everything starting from product packaging
중소기업이라도 제품 포장부터 모든 것을 바꿔야 한다
It's not easy either
그것도 쉽지 않죠
right?
오른쪽?
Do you know what it means to change your brand identity now ?
지금 브랜드 아이덴티티를 바꾸는 것이 무엇을 의미하는지 아시나요?
I know, from marketing to promotion
알아요 마케팅부터 프로모션까지
Everything has to be started from scratch
모든 것은 처음부터 시작되어야 한다
-Do you think this is possible? -Team leader
-이것이 가능하다고 생각하시나요? -팀 리더
if we do nothing now
지금 우리가 아무것도 안 하면
The situation will definitely not get better as time goes by
시간이 지나도 상황은 절대 나아지지 않을 것입니다
us…
우리를…
Let’s try it first
먼저 시도해 보자
But it must be promoted by the cosmetics planning team
근데 화장품기획팀에서 홍보해야지
They must come forward
그들은 앞으로 나와야 한다
(Celdex brand redevelopment project)
(Celdex 브랜드 재개발 프로젝트)
What did you say you wanted to do?
무엇을 하고 싶다고 말했나요?
If you don’t want to give up the Serdix brand positioning targeting people in their 20s,
20대를 타겟으로 한 세르딕스 브랜드 포지셔닝을 포기하고 싶지 않다면,
We would have to completely revise the trademark and packaging...
상표와 포장을 완전히 수정해야 할텐데...
no
아니요
I know what you mean, it's written here
무슨 말인지 알아요, 여기에 써있어요
But you said you want to change the brand identity, what is that...
그런데 브랜드 아이덴티티를 바꾸고 싶다고 하셨는데 그게 무슨...
As far as the current situation is concerned, no matter how hard we try, we can't sell better.
현재 상황에 관한 한 아무리 노력해도 더 잘 팔 수는 없습니다.
how do you know?
어떻게 알아?
How can you predict the future?
미래를 어떻게 예측할 수 있나요?
Agent Park Yun-soo
박윤수 요원
I don't think you would make this decision on your own
나는 당신이 스스로 이런 결정을 내릴 것이라고 생각하지 않습니다
Team leader Chi Yinzhen
팀 리더 Chi Yinzhen
I am passionate
나는 열정적이다
Agent Park from your team came here and talked nonsense.
당신네 팀의 박요원이 여기까지 와서 말도 안 되는 소리를 하더군요.
What is going on?
무슨 일이야?
What is nonsense? Have you read the report?
넌센스 란 무엇입니까? 보고서를 읽어보셨나요?
Did you say that after reading the report?
보고서를 읽고 나서 그렇게 말했나요?
She doesn't even know the basics of marketing
마케팅의 기본도 모르는 사람
Socializing and drinking with reporters and internet celebrities all day long
기자, 인터넷 연예인들과 하루 종일 어울리고 술을 마신다.
Why should I read the information she wrote?
그녀가 쓴 정보를 왜 읽어야합니까?
Yes, we drink every day
응, 우리는 매일 술을 마신다
Because of the bad strategies the marketing team came up with
마케팅팀이 생각해낸 잘못된 전략 때문에
It’s all up to us to escort and convince!
호위하고 설득하는 것은 모두 우리에게 달려 있습니다!
Are you finished?
끝났습니까?
-Not yet -Hello
-아직은 아니예요 -안녕하세요
I am agent Kim Jung-hee from the planning team
기획팀 김정희 요원입니다
We've discussed this before
우리는 이전에 이에 대해 논의한 적이 있습니다.
Compared with the target customer group, from trademark to packaging
타겟 고객층과 비교하여 상표부터 포장까지
It's all too old-fashioned
다 너무 구식이야
But the proposals were all rejected by the superiors
하지만 상사는 그 제안을 모두 거절했다.
That's why we keep silent
그렇기 때문에 우리는 침묵을 지킨다
It's not because we didn't notice
우리가 눈치채지 못했기 때문이 아니야
(Se Yong)
(세용)
Agent Liu
리우 요원
You just said you wanted to talk to me, what happened?
방금 나랑 얘기하고 싶다고 했잖아, 무슨 일이야?
Is it Park Cheon-ok's agent from a group?
그룹 출신 박천옥 에이전트인가?
It's because she took maternity leave that you took her place, right?
그 사람이 출산 휴가를 냈기 때문에 당신이 그 자리를 대신한 거죠?
-That's said to be true - What will happen to her after she gives birth?
-그렇다고 합니다. -아이를 낳은 후 그녀는 어떻게 될까요?
Haven't you heard?
못 들었어?
No, I haven't heard of it
아니요, 들어본 적이 없습니다.
Work in Shirong
시롱에서 근무
People who take maternity leave are usually transferred to the customer service team, right?
출산휴가를 쓰는 사람들은 대개 고객서비스팀으로 옮겨지죠?
(Customer Service: Customer Service)
(고객 서비스: 고객 서비스)
Yeah?
응?
right
오른쪽
You don't have this problem, so you don't care.
당신은 이 문제가 없으므로 상관하지 않습니다.
What?
무엇?
Alas
아아
you…
너…
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
Can't you go back to the second group quickly?
빨리 두 번째 그룹으로 돌아갈 수는 없나요?
You are already responsible for many flagship products
당신은 이미 많은 주력 제품을 담당하고 있습니다.
The team leader always returns my press releases
팀장은 항상 내 보도자료를 돌려준다.
It is easier to pass the assessment when handling flagship products
주력 제품 취급 시 평가 통과가 더 쉽습니다.
Don’t you want to be a senior executive?
당신은 고위 임원이되고 싶지 않습니까?
You said that was your dream
그게 네 꿈이었다고 했잖아
Are you feeling very uncomfortable?
많이 불편하시죠?
Yes, I am Yoo Jae-min
네, 유재민입니다
Do you want to complain about protein powder products?
단백질 파우더 제품에 대해 불만을 제기하고 싶으신가요?
OK, wait a moment
알았어, 잠깐만
Which website are you talking about?
어느 웹사이트를 말씀하시는 건가요?
(Genzyme praise)
(젠자임 칭찬해)
“Genzyme…”
“젠자임…”
(Genzyme, come together! Fitness men and women)
(젠자임 함께해요! 피트니스남녀)
(This forum is only visible to members)
(이 포럼은 회원들에게만 보입니다)
(register)
(등록하다)
"Yoo Jae Min"
"유재민"
I'm telling you, Agent Park
말하는데 박요원
Agent Park
박요원
-Yes- Is this kind of failed product rare?
-네- 이런 불량품이 드물죠?
If you work for a long time, you will encounter a lot of baskets
오랫동안 일하다 보면 바구니를 많이 만나게 될 것이다.
How could they all succeed?
어떻게 모두 성공할 수 있었나요?
why did you do this?
왜이 짓을 했나요?
This is my first brand
이게 내 첫 브랜드야
my brand
내 브랜드
A brand that I can tell belongs to me
내가 알 수 있는 브랜드는 내 것이다
So I want it to succeed more
그래서 더 성공했으면 좋겠다
Alas
아아
I didn't expect to hear this answer
이런 대답을 들을 줄은 몰랐다
We don’t have such people in our group, right?
우리 그룹에는 그런 사람이 없잖아요?
No
아니요
It must be very tiring to have juniors like this.
이런 후배들이 있으면 많이 피곤할 것 같아요.
So you have to work hard
그러니까 열심히 일해야지
Go report it
가서 신고해
You can report it
신고하시면 됩니다
But we can't
하지만 우리는 할 수 없습니다
You go report it, if you can
신고할 수 있으면 가서 신고하세요
Absolutely not!
절대적으로하지!
Don’t even think about it!
그것에 대해 생각조차 하지 마세요!
(Office of the Director of Public Relations Office)
(홍보실장실)
Agent Park
박요원
Come with me with the report
보고서를 가지고 나와 함께 가세요
Have you told the planning team?
기획팀에 말했나요?
Yes
예
The planning team has long noticed this problem
기획팀에서는 이 문제를 오랫동안 인지해왔습니다.
So…
그래서…
This should be reported by the planning team, right?
이건 기획팀에서 보고해야겠죠?
If you want to change your brand identity
브랜드 아이덴티티를 바꾸고 싶다면
We must first admit that the current brand identity has failed
현재의 브랜드 아이덴티티가 실패했다는 점을 먼저 인정해야 합니다.
All products that have just been launched must be recalled
최근 출시된 모든 제품은 리콜되어야 합니다.
Also consider the time it takes to design new packaging
또한 새로운 포장을 디자인하는 데 걸리는 시간도 고려하세요.
Of course, there are also cost considerations for all this.
물론 이 모든 것에 대한 비용 고려 사항도 있습니다.
yes
예
It is precisely because of the reasons you mentioned
바로 당신이 언급한 이유 때문이에요.
Let me be clear this isn't going to be easy
분명히 말하지만 이건 쉽지 않을 거야
But regardless of the attribution of responsibility
하지만 책임의 귀속 여부와 상관없이
I think someone has to give an opinion
누군가 의견을 제시해야 할 것 같아요
based on certain circumstances
특정 상황에 따라
The planning team said it was unable to report in person
기획팀은 직접 보고할 수 없다고 했는데요.
but we can
하지만 우리는 할 수 있어요
besides
게다가
We think there should be room for improvement if we have your help.
여러분의 도움이 있다면 개선의 여지가 있을 것이라고 생각합니다.
I will study it slowly again
천천히 다시 공부해볼게요
Can you email it to me?
이메일로 보내주실 수 있나요?
(Se Yong)
(세용)
I am Chi Yinzhen
나는 치인젠이다
I'm Shin Ji-hyo from the Public Relations Team 3
홍보3팀 신지효 입니다
I'm Park Yoon-so from the Public Relations Team 3
홍보3팀 박윤소 입니다
The team leader is talking on the phone
팀장님이 전화통화 중이세요
Team leader?
팀 리더?
Team leader…
팀 리더…
What?
무엇?
Please leave your phone number and we will contact you again
전화번호를 남겨주시면 다시 연락드리겠습니다.
good
좋은
Director Koo reported at the senior management meeting
구 이사가 고위 경영진 회의에서 보고
In an executive meeting?
임원 회의 중이신가요?
On it is written the name of the person in charge, Agent Park Yoon-soo.
그 위에는 담당자 박윤수 요원의 이름이 적혀 있다.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Yes, that's right, we report...
네 그렇죠 신고합니다...
No, we don't want to bring the company to its knees.
아니요, 우리는 회사를 무너 뜨리고 싶지 .
We just said what needed to be said
우리는 꼭 해야 할 말만 했을 뿐입니다
It seems that this matter should not be discussed on the phone.
이 문제는 전화로 논의해서는 안 될 것 같습니다.
Really
정말
I heard that even Director Chen didn’t know that it was something you two planned together.
두 사람이 함께 계획한 일이었다는 사실은 첸 감독님도 몰랐다고 들었습니다 .
-What? -How come the organization is in such a mess?
-무엇? -조직이 왜 이렇게 엉망이 됐나요?
Don't you know who to report to first?
누구에게 먼저 보고해야 할지 모르시나요?
Do you girls want to hold hands and play games together?
너희들은 손을 잡고 함께 게임을 하고 싶니?
Chief!
실장!
Your little tricks like this won't make me resign, do you understand?
이런 작은 속임수로는 날 사임할 수 없어, 알겠어?
But you'd better show me clearly
하지만 나에게 명확하게 보여주는 게 좋을 것 같아요
How many people will this report kill?
이 보고서로 인해 얼마나 많은 사람이 죽게 될까요?
understand?
이해하다?
That bastard!
그 놈!
That guy actually broke into someone else's territory
그 사람은 사실 남의 영역에 침입한 거야
What are you doing? What went wrong?
뭐하세요? 무엇이 잘못되었나요?
Does the company have that?
회사에 그런 게 있나요?
What's that called? There is a "Workplace Bullying Prevention and Control Act"!
그거 뭐라고 부르나요? "직장 내 괴롭힘 방지 및 관리에 관한 법률"이 있습니다!
Yes, Shirong should have it, right?
응, 시롱이가 갖고 있어야지?
I think there should be
나는 있어야한다고 생각한다
I must report him and then submit my resignation.
나는 그를 보고한 후 사직서를 제출해야 합니다.
Pool leader
풀 리더
let's go smoke a cigarette
담배 피우러 가자
well done
잘하셨어요
You made that guy Zheng Shouhuan stumble?
그 사람 Zheng Shouhuan을 넘어지게 만들었나요?
Will insist that the old-fashioned image represents a high-end brand
고풍스러운 이미지가 고급 브랜드를 대표한다고 주장할 것이다.
That's Jung Soo-hwan
바로 정수환이다.
Minister Kim doesn’t quite understand
김 장관은 잘 이해하지 못한다.
-That's why I trust him so much - Representative
-그래서 나는 그를 그렇게 신뢰한다 - 대표
I don't need to mess with other departments
다른 부서에 간섭할 필요 없어
- Just use this to bring down the marketing team - Representative
- 그냥 이걸로 마케팅팀을 무너뜨리세요 - 대표님
I'm not reporting to you now who you should take down.
나는 지금 당신이 누구를 쓰러뜨려야 하는지 보고하지 않습니다 .
I'm reporting to you that Serdix must rebuild its brand identity
Serdix가 브랜드 아이덴티티를 다시 구축해야 함을 알려드립니다.
wrong
잘못된
Don't rebuild
재구축하지 마세요
If you ignore it, you will fail.
무시하면 실패합니다.
When the time comes we can't go back and we can only give up this brand.
때가 오면 돌아갈 수 없고 이 브랜드를 포기할 수밖에 없습니다.
Then give up and let it become a failed brand.
그렇다면 포기하고 실패한 브랜드가 되도록 놔두세요.
Minister Kim must take full responsibility
김 장관이 책임져야 한다
I'm happy to see it come to fruition
결실을 맺게 되어 기쁘다
When striking, it must be fatal with one blow
때리면 한방에 치명상이 되어야 한다
I have to make the vice president admit his mistake
부통령이 실수를 인정하게 만들어야 해요
Park Yeon-jo?
朴允昭?
I remember her name
나는 그녀의 이름을 기억한다
Let Park Yoon-soo help me manage social media
박윤수에게 SNS 관리를 도와주세요
I want to treat her to a meal. You can set a date.
그녀에게 식사를 대접하고 싶은데 날짜를 정하시면 됩니다.
You
너
All you need to do is fulfill your duties as chief public relations officer.
당신이 해야 할 일은 최고홍보책임자(CPR)로서의 의무를 다하는 것뿐입니다.
Got it?
알았어요?
(Se Yong)
(세용)
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Director Gu
구 이사
Cosmetics department executive Oh Byung-geun resigned
화장품사업부 오병근 상무 사임
Is this the result you want?
이것이 당신이 원하는 결과입니까?
And we decided to promote Cerdix as planned
그리고 우리는 계획대로 Cerdix를 홍보하기로 결정했습니다.
so…
그래서…
Don't be swayed by a few reports written by an agent-level employee ...
상담원급 직원이 작성한 몇 가지 보고서에 흔들리지 마세요...
You said not to be swayed by a few reports
몇 가지 보도에 흔들리지 말라고 했잖아
Then why would you agree to the resignation of Executive Director Wu Binggen?
그렇다면 왜 Wu Binggen 전무이사의 사임에 동의하시겠습니까?
that is because…
그 이유는…
Initial sales were sluggish…
초동판매 부진…
The reason for the sluggish sales must also be clear.
판매가 부진한 이유도 분명해야 한다.
But
하지만
Why should Wu Binggen be in charge of the executive?
왜 Wu Binggen이 경영진을 책임져야 합니까?
Otherwise, who do you want to be responsible?
그렇지 않으면 누구에게 책임을 묻고 싶나요?
I never said who I wanted to be responsible
난 누구를 책임지고 싶다고 말한 적 없어
Hey, Director Goo!
안녕하세요, 구 감독님!
Director Kim
김 이사
What? What did you say?
무엇? 뭐라고 하셨나요?
I just repeated what you said, what's wrong?
방금 말한 내용을 반복했는데 무슨 문제인가요?
Do you want me to not even use honorifics?
존댓말도 쓰지 않았으면 좋겠어?
you…
너…
“The product we were planning to launch failed
“우리가 출시하려고 했던 제품이 실패했어요.
Then someone from the planning team or sales team must take responsibility and resign.”
그러면 기획팀이나 영업팀 중 누군가 책임을 지고 사퇴해야 한다”고 말했다.
If this is the company culture, is there any employee with a broken head?
이런 회사 문화라면 머리가 아픈 직원이 있을까요?
Would you be willing to be responsible for that product?
당신은 그 제품에 대해 책임을 질 의향이 있습니까?
Which employee will come up with great ideas for merchandise?
어떤 직원이 상품에 대한 훌륭한 아이디어를 생각해 낼까요?
Hello
안녕하세요
You don’t understand anything, why should you talk?
아무것도 이해하지 못하는데 왜 말을 해야 합니까?
Just be your CCO!
당신의 CCO가 되어보세요!
Do you know what that means?
너는이 의미를 아니?
What?
무엇?
If you don’t know, just say you don’t know, why are you yelling?
모르면 그냥 모른다고 왜 소리 지르세요?
Also, please be polite when you talk to me.
또한, 저와 대화하실 때 예의를 갖추시기 바랍니다.
I'm an executive director like you
나도 너처럼 전무이사야
I can't stand it
나는 그것을 참을 수 없다
Hello!
안녕하세요!
besides
게다가
I don't smoke. Don't ask me to come here again.
저는 담배를 피우지 않습니다. 다시는 여기로 오라고 하지 마세요.
That bastard...
그 놈...
for you
당신을 위한
Thanks
감사해요
Cosmetics department
화장품 부문
It's such a mess
정말 엉망이야
That was not my intention in giving the report
보고서를 제출할 의도는 그런 것이 아니었습니다.
But they were totally pissed off
근데 그 사람들 완전 화났어.
The final decision-maker is Director of the Marketing Group Jung Soo-hwan
최종 의사결정자는 정수환 마케팅그룹 이사입니다.
But he escaped unscathed and passed all the responsibility on to them.
그러나 그는 무사히 탈출했고 모든 책임을 그들에게 넘겼습니다.
They say this is Zheng Shouhuan's great victory in Serdix
그들은 이것이 Serdix에서 Zheng Shouhuan의 위대한 승리라고 말합니다.
Because he was about to be promoted to the head of the Strategy Headquarters, but now he was being slandered.
전략본부장으로 승진할 뻔했는데 지금은 비방을 받고 있으니까요.
If he is not careful, he may fall into the abyss.
조심하지 않으면 심연에 빠질 수도 있습니다.
Will anything change?
뭔가 바뀔까요?
Director Goo reported it at the senior management meeting
구 이사가 고위 경영진 회의에 보고했다.
Agent Park
박요원
Someone has to take responsibility first
누군가는 먼저 책임을 져야 한다
Only then will there be the next step
그래야만 다음 단계가 있을 것이다
"Okay, that's it
"알았어, 바로 그거야
Failed? Change them all.”
실패한? 모두 바꿔라.”
Do you think this is possible?
이것이 가능하다고 생각하십니까?
The person who talks about cost and efficiency most often is the vice president
비용과 효율성에 대해 가장 자주 이야기하는 사람은 부사장입니다.
There's no way he could nod in agreement
그 사람이 동의한다는 뜻으로 고개를 끄덕일 리가 없어
Have you seen the nonsense posts?
말도 안되는 게시물을 보셨나요?
What's wrong? What did they say again? Do you want me to resign?
뭐가 문제 야? 그 사람들이 또 뭐라고 말했어요? 내가 사임하길 바라나요?
No, it's not like that
아니요, 그렇지 않아요
They say you are the Joan of Arc of the world
사람들은 당신이 세계의 잔 다르크(Joan of Arc)라고 말해요
Oh, what a corny metaphor, ugh
아, 정말 진부한 비유네요, 윽
Because you bravely brought up what everyone knew but didn’t say anything.
모두가 알면서도 말하지 않은 것을 용감하게 꺼냈기 때문이다 .
What's the use of just bringing it up?
그냥 꺼내기만 하면 무슨 소용이 있나요?
But this has never happened before
하지만 이런 일은 이전에 일어난 적이 없었습니다
There is also a team leader who will not ignore the opinions of employees and will advance or retreat with you.
직원들의 의견을 무시하지 않고 함께 전진하거나 후퇴 하는 팀장도 있습니다 .
Pool leader
풀 리더
what to do?
무엇을 해야 할까요?
And directors who report at senior executive meetings
그리고 고위 임원회의에서 보고하는 이사들
director
감독
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
right
오른쪽
You need this kind of fun at work
직장에서는 이런 재미가 필요해요
Then Agent Park, see you next time
그럼 박요원 다음에 또 만나요
- Come here - See you next time
- 이리와요 - 다음에 또 만나요
come over
이리와
It's not what you think
당신이 생각하는 것과는 다릅니다
What? Not what?
무엇? 뭐라고요?
You just looked like childhood sweethearts
넌 어린 시절의 연인처럼 보였어
Yes, we are childhood sweethearts
그래요, 우리는 어린 시절의 연인입니다
You finally confessed, how many days have you been dating?
드디어 고백했는데, 사귄 지 며칠 됐나요?
no…
아니요…
Park Yunzhao and I have known each other since elementary school.
박윤자오와 저는 초등학교 때부터 알고 지냈어요.
Classmates from Hongguo Elementary School and Hongguo Junior High School
홍궈 초등학교와 홍궈 중학교의 동급생
We have been friends for many years and there is absolutely no way we can become lovers
우리는 수년 동안 친구로 지냈고 연인이 될 수 있는 방법은 전혀 없습니다.
-understand? -wrong…
-이해하다? -잘못된…
No, this is impossible, no...
아니, 이건 불가능해, 아니...
And I have someone I like
그리고 내가 좋아하는 사람이 있는데
So don’t make random arrangements
그러니 무작위로 준비하지 마세요
No, you're lying
아니, 거짓말하고 있는 거야
wrong…
잘못된…
Do you need to be so surprised?
그렇게까지 놀랄 필요가 있나요?
I really like to make a fuss
나는 소란을 피우는 걸 정말 좋아한다.
Come here quickly
빨리 여기로 와
I have God-given intuition, I can't possibly make a mistake
신이 주신 직감이 있어 절대 실수할 수 없어
No, this is a lie, you are lying to me
아니 이건 거짓말이야, 넌 나한테 거짓말을 하는 거야
This is not true…
이것은 사실이 아니다…
(Se Yong)
(세용)
I heard that Executive Wu has submitted his resignation.
우 간부가 사표를 제출했다는 소식을 들었습니다.
-Who said that? - Agent Kim Chung Hee told me just now
-누가 말했다? - 김정희 요원이 방금 말했어요.
She said that the entire team leader may be resigning soon.
그녀는 팀 리더 전체가 곧 사임할 수도 있다고 말했습니다.
What to do now?
이제 무엇을 해야 할까요?
What else can be done?
또 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
They can only survive in their respective positions
각자의 위치에서만 살아남을 수 있다
That's all we can do
그게 우리가 할 수 있는 전부야
Agent Park
박요원
One of the things I hate the most
내가 제일 싫어하는 것 중 하나
It's just that there is a reporting system but some people don't take it seriously and do whatever they want.
단지 신고 제도가 있을 뿐인데, 이를 심각하게 받아들이지 않고 하고 싶은 대로 하는 사람들도 있습니다.
The company will not differentiate between agents, section chiefs, and department heads for no reason.
회사는 이유 없이 대리인, 과장, 부서장을 차별 .
I think today is an exception
오늘은 예외인 것 같아요
Have you come to our office in person?
저희 사무실에 직접 오셨나요?
so what?
그래서 뭐?
I don't think it should be because of me and this report
저와 이 보고서 때문은 아닌 것 같아요
Let the sales team or planning team take responsibility
영업팀이나 기획팀이 책임을 지게 하세요.
If someone has to take responsibility, I will take it up
누군가 책임을 져야 한다면 내가 짊어지겠다 .
I think this is right
내 생각엔 이게 맞는 것 같아
Agent Park
박요원
-Yes -Why are you responsible?
-네 -왜 책임이 있나요?
Those who shoulder the responsibility should be held responsible
책임을 지는 사람은 책임을 져야 한다
but you…
하지만 당신은…
you are nothing
넌 아무것도 아니야
This sentence means
이 문장의 뜻은
You are nothing, you cannot be responsible for anything
넌 아무것도 아니야, 아무것도 책임질 수 없어
Agent Park Yun-soo
박윤수 요원
Take a good look carefully
잘 살펴보세요
What are the consequences of being pretentious?
허식의 결과는 무엇입니까?
you can go out
넌 나갈 수 있어
It seems you are going to get off work
퇴근하실 것 같네요
right
오른쪽
Park Yeon-jo?
朴允昭?
She came to me just now and said that she would be responsible
방금 나한테 와서 자기가 책임지겠다고 했어
Really shocking
정말 충격적이야
Does she really not understand how the company works?
그녀는 정말로 회사가 어떻게 돌아가는지 이해하지 못하는 걸까요?
Or is it because she worked in an agency before?
아니면 이전에 소속사에서 일했기 때문인가요?
What would you do if Serdix's situation didn't improve ?
Serdix의 상황이 개선되지 않으면 어떻게 하시겠습니까 ?
What?
무엇?
If you mess up in the end
결국 망하면
Who do you think the Vice President or Executive Kim will hold accountable?
부회장이나 김 상무는 누구에게 책임을 물을 것이라고 생각하시나요?
(Se Yong)
(세용)
-I'll leave first . -Okay
- 나 먼저 갈게 - 알았어
- Be careful on the road - Goodbye
- 길 조심하세요 - 안녕
(Ang’s Bakery)
(앙스 베이커리)
Masaaki
允昭
How are you doing?
어떻게 지내세요?
Director Park, I heard you went to a good place , no wonder you look rosy...
박 감독님, 좋은 곳으로 가셨다고 들었는데 , 얼굴이 장밋빛이군요...
Working in a big company is tiring, right?
대기업에서 일하는 건 피곤하지 않나요?
Of course, it must be very tiring
물론 많이 피곤하겠지만
No, I'm fine
아냐 난 괜찮아
come on
어서 해봐요
Thanks
감사해요
Hello
안녕하세요
Take your time, okay? drink slowly
천천히 시간을 가져라, 알았지? 천천히 마시다
This hurts the stomach
이거 배가 아프다
It doesn't matter if I hurt my stomach
배가 아파도 상관없어
That's nothing
그건 별거 아니야
I caused all the team leaders to suffer for no reason
아무 이유 없이 팀장들 모두를 고생시켰어요
Didn't the planning team ask you to report it?
기획팀에서 신고하라고 하지 않았나요?
That's still my fault
그건 아직도 ​​내 잘못이야
They also made a choice
그들도 선택을 했어
Otherwise, how could all the team leaders agree?
그렇지 않으면 어떻게 팀 리더들이 모두 동의할 수 있겠습니까?
But I still have a responsibility
하지만 나에겐 아직 책임이 있어
I said I would be responsible
내가 책임지겠다고 했어
Then they said no
그러자 그들은 안 된다고 하더군요
Because I am not yet in a responsible position
나는 아직 책임 있는 위치에 있지 않기 때문에
That's true
그건 사실이야
I'm really sad
정말 슬프다
represent
대표하다
Well, I'm listening
응, 듣고 있어
OK, tell me
알았어, 말해봐
You
너
All you need to do is fulfill your duties as chief public relations officer.
당신이 해야 할 일은 최고홍보책임자(CPR)로서의 의무를 다하는 것뿐입니다.
You don’t understand anything, why should you talk?
아무것도 이해하지 못하는데 왜 말을 해야 합니까?
Just be your CCO!
당신의 CCO가 되어보세요!
Internal culture improvement plan?
내부 문화 개선 방안은?
This is a plan to renew and reform the internal culture
내부 문화를 쇄신하고 개혁하려는 계획이다.
As chief public relations officer, I must do my job well
홍보담당자로서 맡은 일을 잘해야 한다
You also said that you want to be a good communicator
당신도 좋은 커뮤니케이터가 되고 싶다고 하더군요
Internal culture?
내부 문화?
I want to improve employee engagement through this project
나는 이 프로젝트를 통해 직원 참여도를 높이고 싶습니다.
Good intention
좋은 의도
Go push it
가서 밀어봐
OK
좋아요
correct
옳은
About Serdix…
세르딕스 소개…
I think the font size can be larger
글꼴 크기가 더 커도 될 것 같아요
-Okay -Please.
-알겠습니다. -제발요.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
yes
예
Really?
정말?
Is it true? Team leader
사실인가요? 팀 리더
That's great, bye
훌륭해요, 안녕
Agent Park
박요원
The company decided to rebuild Seldex
회사는 Seldex를 재구축하기로 결정했습니다.
I heard it was the vice president's decision.
부사장님의 결정이라고 들었습니다.
All group leaders will remain in office
모든 그룹 리더는 직위를 유지합니다.
she will stay
그녀는 머물 것이다
I just received the report
방금 보고서를 받았습니다.
They decided to overhaul Serdix’s brand identity
그들은 Serdix의 브랜드 아이덴티티를 재정비하기로 결정했습니다.
their whole weekend
주말 내내
All are simulating and evaluating cost efficiency
모두 비용 효율성을 시뮬레이션하고 평가하고 있습니다.
but…
하지만…
how? Any questions?
어떻게? 질문이 있으신가요?
The person who convinced the vice president was Zheng Shouhuan
부회장을 설득한 사람은 정수환이었다.
This means that the vice president ultimately sided with Jung Soo Hwan.
결국 부회장이 정수환 편을 들었다는 뜻이다.
In this case
이 경우
Only Executive Wu resigned inexplicably and I gained nothing.
우 임원만이 이유 없이 사임했고 저는 아무것도 얻지 못했습니다.
It was you who founded the brand Serdix
Serdix라는 브랜드를 창립한 사람은 바로 당신이었습니다.
If Serdix succeeds, it's all your fault.
Serdix가 성공한다면 그것은 모두 당신의 잘못입니다.
My dad was still alive before
우리 아버지는 그 전에도 살아계셨어.
When I was the head of the strategy department, I felt much more relaxed.
전략부장을 맡으면서 마음이 훨씬 편해졌어요.
(Representative Seo Dong-hun)
(대표 서동훈)
It’s not just because of this project
단지 이 프로젝트 때문만은 아니다
I'm just a little tired
그냥 좀 피곤할 뿐이야
No matter how hard you try, as long as the customer is not satisfied
아무리 노력해도 고객이 만족하지 않는 한
Months and weeks of our efforts were all in vain.
몇 달, 몇 주에 걸친 우리의 노력은 모두 허사였습니다.
I know this is the norm for agencies
나는 이것이 대행사의 표준이라는 것을 알고 있습니다.
But it’s too hard
하지만 너무 힘들어요
Have you considered taking a break first?
먼저 휴식을 취하는 것을 고려해 보셨나요?
I'll take a break and come back
좀 쉬었다가 돌아올게요
Will things change?
상황이 바뀔까요?
More work, less pay
더 많은 일을 하고, 더 적은 급여를 받자
I don't think this fundamental issue will change
이런 근본적인 문제는 변하지 않을 것 같아요
The representatives are good people.
대표님들 좋은 분들이세요.
So I have been troubled for a long time
그래서 오랫동안 고민했어요
Director Chen does have the habit of talking nonsense when he is excited.
첸 감독은 흥분하면 헛소리를 하는 버릇이 있다 .
Is it bad?
나쁜가요?
How exactly do you work?
정확히 어떻게 일하시나요?
I…
나…
How much I cherish global communication
나는 글로벌 커뮤니케이션을 얼마나 소중히 여깁니다.
You made it so bad for me?
너 때문에 나한테 그렇게 나쁜 짓을 한 거야?
Nako, Chief...
나개, 실장…
If Global Communications does good things
글로벌커뮤니케이션즈가 좋은 일을 한다면
This result will never occur
이런 결과는 절대 발생하지 않습니다
You should run the event well and increase sales.
행사를 잘 운영해서 매출을 늘려야 합니다.
That's why I hired you!
그래서 내가 당신을 고용했어요!
sorry
죄송합니다
You have some bad employees to make things like this, right?
이런 걸 만드는 나쁜 직원도 있잖아요 ?
I want to call all the people in and listen to them reflect on their mistakes one by one.
모든 분들을 불러들여 각자의 잘못을 반성하는 소리를 듣고 싶습니다 .
No
아니요
please don't do this
제발 이러지 마세요
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
This is my fault
이건 내 잘못이야
You are disappointed by the failure to achieve the results you expected
기대했던 결과를 얻지 못해 실망합니다.
it's all my fault
그것은 모두 내 잘못이야
sorry
죄송합니다
This is the fate of agents
이것이 요원의 운명이다
Speaking of which, what should Director An do?
그런데 안 원장은 어떻게 해야 하나?
she looks tired
그 사람 피곤해 보여요
What can we do for her?
우리는 그녀를 위해 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
Is there any other way but to accept her resignation ?
그녀의 사임을 받아들이는 것 외에 다른 방법은 없나요 ?
Actually, I've been worried about this for a long time.
사실 저는 이 부분에 대해 오랫동안 고민했어요.
“How can we make Global Communications employees feel proud of their work?
“Global Communications 직원들이 자신의 업무에 대해 자부심을 갖게 하려면 어떻게 해야 할까요 ?
How do you keep them from feeling discouraged by staying in an agency? "
소속사에 남아서 그들이 낙담하지 않도록 하려면 어떻게 해야 하나요 ? "
-Senior -What's wrong?
- 선배 - 무슨 일이에요?
Should we introduce a flexible salary incentive system?
유연한 급여 인센티브 제도를 도입해야 할까요?
Employees decide their own workload
직원들이 스스로 업무량을 결정
let them get it
그들이 그것을 얻게 놔두세요
Better than the annual salary of big companies
대기업 연봉보다 낫네
Great, that's a good idea
좋아요, 그거 좋은 생각이에요
But that may increase the competitive atmosphere within the company
그러나 이는 회사 내 경쟁 분위기를 증가시킬 수 있습니다.
But you can still consider it
하지만 그래도 고려해 볼 수는 있어요
We can gradually improve the system
점진적으로 시스템을 개선할 수 있습니다.
(Lin Zhixian represents the social media management project)
(Lin Zhixian은 소셜 미디어 관리 프로젝트를 대표합니다)
I revised and sorted out this plan at your request
귀하의 요청에 따라 이 계획을 수정하고 정리했습니다.
1. Content of the post
1. 게시물의 내용
2. Frequency of posting
2. 게시 빈도
3. Risk
3. 위험
(Management Policy)
(경영방침)
learn
배우다
very nice
아주 좋은
- Then I'll forward it to the representative. - Okay.
- 그럼 대표님께 전달할게요 - 알겠습니다.
(New email, Representative Lin Zhixian)
(새 이메일, Lin Zhixian 대표)
(Lin Zhixian represents the social media management project)
(Lin Zhixian은 소셜 미디어 관리 프로젝트를 대표합니다)
let's go
갑시다
Wait, Director
잠깐만요, 감독님
I wanted to thank you about Serdix.
Serdix에 대해 감사의 말씀을 전하고 싶었습니다.
if there was not you…
당신이 없었다면…
I just did what I had to do
난 그냥 내가 해야 할 일을 했을 뿐이야
So you don't have to thank me
그러니까 나한테 고마워할 필요는 없어
but…
하지만…
if it weren't for you
당신이 아니었다면
nothing will change
아무것도 변하지 않을 것이다
That’s why the company should thank you
이래서 회사는 감사해야 해
Right?
오른쪽?
director
감독
We're going to be late, let's go
우리 늦을 것 같아, 가자
OK
좋아요
Welcome, Park Yoon-so!
안녕하세요, 박윤소님!
Thanks
감사해요
- Sit down - Okay
- 앉으세요 - 알았어
I don’t know about today’s non-menu dishes.
오늘의 비메뉴 요리는 어떨지 모르겠네요.
There's only one menu here, you know that right?
여기는 메뉴가 하나뿐인 거 아시죠?
Know
알다
And your social media plan
그리고 소셜 미디어 계획
I've seen it
나 그거 봤었 어
There are too many things I'm not allowed to do.
나에게는 허락되지 않은 일이 너무 많습니다.
look at this
이거 봐요
“Don’t post too frequently
“너무 자주 게시하지 마세요.
You may be left with messages attacking company representatives for doing nothing.”
아무것도 하지 않은 회사 대표를 공격하는 메시지가 남을 수도 있다 ”고 말했다.
That's no problem
그건 문제없어요
"Don't upload personal collections
"개인 컬렉션을 업로드하지 마세요.
When a company does not perform well, it may be reprimanded
회사가 실적이 좋지 않으면 질책을 받을 수도 있습니다.
A maximum of two posts related to celebrity artists can be posted in a month
연예인 아티스트 관련 게시물은 한 달에 최대 2개까지 게시 가능합니다.
Posts about working in the office
사무실에서 일하는 것에 관한 게시물
Be aware of stacked files”
누적된 파일에 주의하세요”
-I just don’t want to run social media anymore . -That’s it.
-더 이상 소셜 미디어를 운영하고 싶지 않습니다 .
If you don’t have the confidence to comply , it’s better not to start.
준수할 자신이 없다면 시작하지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Park Yun Zhao, do you think so too?
박윤자 씨도 그렇게 생각하시나요?
I hope
나는 희망
you can start a business
당신은 사업을 시작할 수 있습니다
There are research results showing
보여주는 연구결과가 있습니다
The behavior of representatives will not only affect the corporate image
대표자의 행동은 기업 이미지에만 영향을 미치는 것이 아닙니다
Even the customer’s favorability towards the product
제품에 대한 고객의 호감도까지
will also be significantly affected
도 크게 영향을 받을 것이다
That's right
좋아요
Yes, Elon Musk also loves to post.
예, Elon Musk도 게시하는 것을 좋아합니다.
Just do it
그냥 해
This is what I propose, just do it
이게 내가 제안하는 거야, 그냥 해라
But don't be too rigid, okay?
하지만 너무 딱딱하게 굴지는 마세요. 알겠죠?
Do you agree?
동의하시나요?
What are you doing? Why are you looking at her?
뭐하세요? 왜 그녀를 보고 있나요?
Look at me, okay?
나 좀 봐, 알았지?
The PR office publishes three articles a week...
홍보실은 일주일에 세 편의 기사를 낸다.
No, it's what you want to write anyway , so give me some free space, okay?
아니, 어차피 니가 쓰고 싶은 글이니까 여유 공간 좀 줘 알았지?
OK
좋아요
People definitely want to see the representative’s daily life and private appearance.
사람들은 대표의 일상과 사적인 모습을 꼭 보고 싶어 한다 .
That's right!
좋아요!
Oh, Park Yun Zhao, I'm gradually developing a crush on you.
아, 박윤자오, 점점 당신에게 반하게 되는군요.
Thanks
감사해요
Okay, now let's eat
알았어 이제 먹자
They have been waiting for a long time
그들은 오랫동안 기다려 왔습니다.
Jump like this
이렇게 뛰어내려
-Hey, the sky is really beautiful . -Yes.
-아, 하늘이 정말 아름다워요 .
-We are beautiful. -Yu Zhen dances so well.
-우리는 아름답습니다.- 유젠은 춤을 너무 잘 춥니다.
Hey, I've made a lot of progress after learning from Yu Zhen
안녕하세요 유진님한테 배워서 많이 발전했어요
Yes, I can finally see your dancing skills
그래요, 드디어 당신의 춤 실력을 볼 수 있어요
Hey, I really improved a lot after Yu Zhen taught me
야 유진이한테 가르쳐주고 나 진짜 많이 좋아졌어
Yes, a lot of progress has been made
네, 많이 발전했어요
To be honest, I didn't dare to say it before
솔직히 예전엔 감히 말하지 못했는데
You dance very well now
지금은 춤을 정말 잘 춘다
-Are you in love? -How can it be?
-사랑에 빠졌나요? - 어떻게 그럴 수 있나요?
How is it impossible?
어떻게 불가능합니까?
You have everything, it’s not an exaggeration to fall in love
넌 모든 걸 다 가졌어 사랑에 ​​빠진다고 해도 과언이 아니야
What does it mean that I have everything?
내가 모든 것을 가지고 있다는 것은 무엇을 의미합니까?
Your family is rich, right?
네 가족은 부자지, 그렇지?
You occasionally take your dad's car to school in the morning
아침에 가끔 아빠 차를 타고 학교에 가세요.
Isn’t that a super expensive imported car?
완전 비싼 수입차 아닌가요?
besides
게다가
You have good grades and a smart mind
넌 성적도 좋고 머리도 똑똑해
dance well
잘 춘다
Looks beautiful
아름답다
It's just perfect
정말 완벽해요
Look, you have it all
봐, 넌 다 가졌어
You are the complete opposite of me...
넌 나와 완전 반대야...
What's this? Actually sending a text message? Is she from the Joseon era?
이건 뭐죠? 실제로 문자 메시지를 보내나요? 조선시대 사람인가?
(Yoo Jin, mom has returned to Korea)
(유진이 엄마가 한국으로 돌아왔어요)
(You didn’t answer the phone, so I sent you a text message)
(전화를 받지 않으셔서 문자를 보냈습니다)
(Are you free right now?)
(지금 시간 있어요?)
Her name is Goo Yi Jung
이름이 구이정인 사람
After giving birth to me, he abandoned me when I was two years old
나를 낳은 뒤, 내가 두 살이 되던 해에 나를 버리셨다.
People who go to study abroad
유학 가시는 분들
She returned to Korea a while ago
그녀는 얼마 전 한국으로 돌아왔다.
so
그래서
Are you so angry that you don’t want to contact her?
너무 화가 나서 그 사람에게 연락하기 싫나요?
Um
음
I'm almost mad
나는 거의 화가 났어요
Then why don't you delete the message?
그럼 메시지를 삭제하는 게 어때요?
In short
요컨대
What's the use of her mother if she only gets into trouble ?
엄마가 문제만 일으키면 무슨 소용이 있겠습니까 ?
Maybe it would be better without a mother
어쩌면 엄마가 없는 게 더 나을지도 몰라
I thought so
나는 그렇게 생각했다
Hey, let's go
야, 가자
Let's go, it's time to ring the clock
가자, 이제 시계를 울릴 시간이야
Let's go
갑시다
Section Chief Meng knows? How does he know?
멍 과장은 알고 있나요? 그 사람은 어떻게 알죠?
- I told him - Hello
- 내가 그 사람에게 말했어요 - 안녕하세요
He always misunderstands our relationship
그 사람은 늘 우리 관계를 오해하고 있어
It's troublesome to lie all the time
맨날 거짓말하는 것도 귀찮아
Hey, by the way, that Representative Xu
아 그런데 그 쑤 대표님
When you were drunk at that time, I took you home
그 때 술취해서 집에 데려다줬는데
I talked to him on the phone
나는 그와 전화로 이야기를 나눴다.
He is worried about you
그 사람이 당신을 걱정하고 있어요
He seems to have a crush on you, right?
그 사람이 당신에게 반한 것 같죠?
There's none?
아무것도 없나요?
There should be
있어야 한다
I can tell at a glance
한눈에 알 수 있어요
No
아니요
Come on, it seems he hasn't confessed to you yet
어서, 아직 그 사람이 너한테 고백을 안 한 것 같구나.
No, why are there such people these days?
아니 요즘엔 왜 그런 사람들이 있는 걸까요?
An American-style guy like him
그 사람 같은 아메리칸 스타일의 남자
You usually go to the other person directly for a date, right?
데이트를 할 때 상대방에게 직접 가는 경우가 많죠?
I already told you that's not the case
이미 그런 건 아니라고 말했잖아
how about you? What do you think?
당신은 어떤가요? 어떻게 생각하나요?
If you are also interested in him, then take the initiative to ask him out.
당신도 그 사람에게 관심이 있다면 솔선하여 그에게 데이트 신청을 하세요.
(I)
(나)
Hello, Yoo Jae-min
안녕하세요 유재민님
how? You don't like him?
어떻게? 당신은 그를 좋아하지 않습니까?
Yeah, I don't like him very much
응, 나 그 사람 별로 안 좋아해
I don't know why I just don't like him
왜 내가 그 사람을 좋아하지 않는지 모르겠어요
Do you want to date me?
나랑 데이트할래?
-Um?
-음?
What?
무엇?
Date me?
나랑 데이트해?
Um
음
OK
좋아요
Go on a date, or just pretend
데이트를 하든, 아니면 그냥 척 하든가
Hey, I’m almost dying of loneliness when I’m single.
아, 난 싱글일 때 외로움에 거의 죽을 지경이야.
This is the benefit of having friends
친구가 있으면 이런게 장점이지
I'm not joking
나 장난하는 거 아니야
What?
무엇?
I said I wasn't kidding
나는 농담이 아니라고 말했다.
-What? -Don't ask anymore
-무엇? -더 이상 묻지 마세요
I…
나…
Never thought about it
그것에 대해 생각해 본 적이 없습니다.
I would say this kind of thing in broad daylight and in the company tea room.
저는 대낮에도 , 회사 다실에서도 이런 말을 하곤 했어요 .
Then don't say it
그럼 말하지 마
Don't say it, Yun Zhao
말하지 마 윤자오
Do not say
말 하지마
(rest area)
(휴게소)
(Se Yong)
(세용)
I first got off work
처음으로 퇴근했어요
Jaemin, are you free?
재민아, 시간 있어?
Are you free?
시간 돼?
Do you want to go for a drink?
한잔하러 갈래?
Cai Min
카이 민
What are you looking at?
무엇을 보고 있나요?
Let's go
갑시다
Where are you going? You don't usually take the bus, right?
어디 가세요? 넌 보통 버스를 타지 않지, 그렇지?
Are you going to Utopia? go together
유토피아에 가시나요? 함께 가다
Hello, Xiao Zhao
안녕하세요, 샤오자오 님
You go to Utopia by yourself, I won’t go
유토피아는 너 혼자 가, 난 안 가
Masaaki
允昭
what?
무엇?
I have someone I like
좋아하는 사람이 있어요
I fell in love with her again
나는 그녀와 다시 사랑에 빠졌다
"again"?
"다시"?
The guy I met in San Diego
샌디에이고에서 만난 남자
I saw her again
나는 그녀를 다시 보았다
I'm attracted to her again
나는 또 그 사람에게 끌린다.
Started to care about her again
그녀에게 다시 관심이 생기기 시작했어요
so
그래서
Have you decided to get back together with her?
그녀와 다시 만나기로 결정하셨나요?
not yet
아직 아님
I haven't told her yet
난 아직 그녀에게 말하지 않았어
-Why? -I'm afraid of being rejected by her again
-왜? - 그 사람에게 다시 거절당할까봐 두렵다.
idiot
바보
The first time, I just thought I was dumped in a daze.
처음에는 그냥 멍하니 멍하니 있는 줄 알았어요.
But I've had a taste of that
하지만 난 그런 맛을 본 적이 있어
But have to go through it a second time?
하지만 두 번째로 통과해야 합니까?
I really have no confidence
정말 자신감이 없어
Then you want to continue to have a crush on her?
그럼 계속 그 사람을 좋아하고 싶나요?
My feelings for her are not love yet
그 사람을 향한 내 마음은 아직 사랑이 아니야
What?
무엇?
I feel moved and care about her very much
나는 그녀를 매우 감동시키고 걱정합니다.
i do like her
나는 그녀를 좋아한다
But I'm not sure if that's love
하지만 그게 사랑인지는 잘 모르겠어
Love is nothing special
사랑은 특별한 것이 아니다
Those feelings gathered together are love
모인 그 마음은 사랑이다
I've liked you since I was a child
난 어렸을 때부터 당신을 좋아했어요
I thought this was wrong
나는 이것이 틀렸다고 생각했다.
i can't like you
나는 당신을 좋아할 수 없습니다
Convince yourself that we are just friends and restrain your feelings for you
우리는 단지 친구일 뿐이라고 스스로 확신 하고 당신에 대한 감정을 억제하세요
Why didn't you tell me then?
그때 왜 나한테 말하지 않았어?
At that time, I felt that we were not the same kind of people
그땐 우리가 그런 사람이 아닌 걸 느꼈어
You are like someone living in another world
넌 마치 다른 세상에 사는 사람 같아
Someone I can't catch
잡을 수 없는 사람
people i can't touch
내가 만질 수 없는 사람들
You were volunteering in Africa while I was worrying about rent.
나는 집세 걱정을 하고 있을 때 당신은 아프리카에서 자원봉사를 하고 있었다 .
It feels like you are a different person
마치 다른 사람이 된 것 같은 느낌
but
하지만
Now we are in the same company
이제 우리는 같은 회사에 있습니다
Meet every day
매일 만나요
So I seem to be greedy
그래서 욕심이 많은 것 같아요
I'm no different from you
나도 너랑 다르지 않아
we live in the same world
우리는 같은 세상에 살고 있어요
so
그래서
That's why I had that thought
그래서 그런 생각을 하게 됐어요
I think I might like you now
이제 내가 널 좋아할 것 같아
After I said it, I felt much more relaxed
그 말을 하고 나니 마음이 한결 편해졌습니다
Even though I'm so embarrassed
너무 부끄러워도
Do you want tissues?
티슈를 원하시나요?
Well, bring it
자, 가져오세요
I don't
나는 아니에요
Am I someone who carries tissues with me everywhere?
나는 어디든 휴지를 가지고 다니는 사람인가?
Isn't it nice to look at each other like this?
이렇게 서로를 바라보는 게 좋지 않나요?
Hello…
안녕하세요…
You're right, that's great
당신 말이 맞아요, 정말 좋아요
You are in a lovelorn state now, so I will let you go
지금은 사랑에 빠진 상태니까 보내줄게
Do you understand?
이해했나요?
I will never forgive you next time
다음번엔 절대로 용서하지 않을 거야
-This station is -You get off first
-이 역은 -먼저 내리세요
Dongsan-dong Korea District Heating Company Station
동산동 한국지역난방공사역
Why? We'll be at Utopia soon
왜? 우리는 곧 Utopia에 도착할 거예요
I was rejected, I have to feel sad again
거절당해서 또 슬퍼해야지
You get off the car first
먼저 차에서 내려
good
좋은
If you feel more comfortable that way
그 편이 더 편하다면
what happened again? What happened again this time?
또 무슨 일이 일어난 거야? 이번에는 또 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Oh, it's true
아, 사실이에요
Xiao Zhao confessed to me
샤오자오가 나에게 고백했다
She said she likes me
그 사람이 날 좋아한다고 했어
What?
무엇?
Just now during the day
지금 막 낮에
In the company's tea room
회사 찻집에서
Oh my god
맙소사
Wow, it really looks like her style
와 진짜 스타일 닮았다
But I rejected her
하지만 나는 그녀를 거절했다
I also have people I like
나도 좋아하는 사람이 있어
Hey, who is the person you like?
야, 네가 좋아하는 사람은 누구야?
Our company's chief public relations officer
우리 회사의 최고 홍보 책임자
What? what does that mean?
무엇? 그게 무슨 뜻이야?
Serong's chief public relations officer is the woman in San Diego
세롱 홍보담당자는 샌디에고에 사는 여성
This is destiny, right?
이건 운명이죠?
But I don’t know if I can confess like Yun Zhao
그런데 윤자오처럼 고백할 수 있을지 모르겠어요
Hey, you've already tried it once
야, 너 이미 한 번 해봤잖아
He was even harshly rejected
심지어는 심하게 거절당하기도 했다
You are pestering others by doing this.
당신은 이렇게 함으로써 다른 사람을 괴롭히고 있습니다.
no…
아니요…
Things have changed, okay?
상황이 바뀌었어요, 그렇죠?
I was too young then
그때는 너무 어렸어
I feel like she lives in another world and...
그녀는 다른 세상에 살고 있는 것 같은 느낌이 듭니다...
-You're crazy -Hey
- 미쳤구나 - 야
I just said the exact same thing as Yun Zhao
방금 윤자오랑 똑같은 말을 했어
(Yoo Jae-min)
(유재민)
-Hello? -You answered the phone?
-안녕하세요? -전화 받았어요?
What's your business?
당신의 사업은 무엇입니까?
Are you busy now?
지금 바쁘신가요?
No, I'm not busy
아니요, 안 바빠요
So can you give me a moment?
그럼 잠시만 시간을 내주실 수 있나요?
Where are you?
어디세요?
(Internal Culture Improvement Plan Recruitment Task Force)
(내부문화개선기획단 채용TF)
Our three groups are going to send people to the internal culture improvement project team
우리 세 그룹은 내부 문화 개선 프로젝트 팀 에 사람들을 파견할 예정입니다.
Who is going?
누가 가나요?
Going there shouldn’t reduce the workload, right?
거기에 가면 업무량이 줄어들면 안 되겠죠?
-Team leader- No.
-팀장- 아니요.
Is that just business as usual and then add this on top of that?
그것은 평소대로의 일이고 여기에 이것을 추가합니까?
This is how the task force works
태스크포스는 이렇게 일한다
Where is Agent Park?
파크 요원은 어디에 있나요?
Can contract personnel also participate?
계약직 직원도 참여할 수 있나요?
In fact, I just came to this world not long ago
사실 나는 이 세상에 온 지 얼마 안 됐어.
So I don’t know much about Se Yong’s culture yet.
그래서 저는 아직 세용이의 문화에 대해 잘 모릅니다.
You should know Seyong’s culture better than anyone else, right?
세용이의 문화는 누구보다 잘 알아야겠죠?
I would like to go if I could participate
참가할 수 있다면 가고 싶습니다.
“Not in a rigid, hierarchical system
“경직되고 계층적인 시스템이 아닌
An organization that concentrates power in one person
한 사람에게 권력을 집중시키는 조직
Instead, create a system that empowers individuals to make decisions and change based on the situation.
대신 개인이 상황에 따라 결정을 내리고 변화할 수 있도록 권한을 부여하는 시스템을 만드세요.
An approach to an agile and responsive organization”
민첩하고 대응력이 뛰어난 조직에 대한 접근 방식”
Not bad, right?
나쁘지 않죠?
-Yeah yeah
- 응, 응
So
그래서
Who is going?
누가 가나요?
Team leader, the graduation ceremony of the college student experience group will be held today.
팀장님 오늘 대학생체험단 졸업식이 진행됩니다.
Oh my God, it's finally over.
맙소사, 드디어 끝났네요.
Otherwise, do we have to experience it for a lifetime? Do you think they will never grow old?
그렇지 않으면 평생 경험해야 합니까? 당신은 그들이 결코 늙지 않을 것이라고 생각합니까?
Really
정말
You are the one
당신은 바로 그 사람입니다
good
좋은
Hello
안녕하세요
Is this an internal culture improvement task force?
사내문화개선TF인가요?
No one else has come yet
아직 다른 사람은 안 왔어
right
오른쪽
We decided by drawing lots
추첨으로 결정했어요
-What? -Human resources are determined by drawing lots.
-무엇? -인재는 추첨을 통해 결정됩니다.
I'm so unlucky
나는 너무 운이 좋지 않다
I've never won a prize
나는 상을 받은 적이 없다.
I just have good luck in this kind of thing
난 그냥 이런 일이 있어서 행운을 빌어
I volunteered because I wanted to participate
참여하고 싶어서 자원했습니다
Why haven't you come yet?
왜 아직 안 오셨어요?
I plan to work here for the rest of my life.
나는 남은 생애 동안 여기서 일할 계획입니다.
I need this opportunity
이 기회가 필요해
Work that distracts me and allows me to work hard
나를 주의를 산만하게 하고 내가 열심히 일할 수 있게 해주는 일
But it must be very painful to see him every day.
그런데 그 사람을 매일 보는 게 많이 괴로울 것 같아요.
We don't meet every day
우리는 매일 만나지 않아요
As long as I don't go out of my way to see him, we won't run into each other.
내가 그 사람을 만나러 나가지 않는 한, 우리는 서로 마주치지 않을 거예요.
Why? Don't you work together anymore?
왜? 이제 같이 일 안 하시나요?
Xiaomin is temporarily transferred to a group.
Xiaomin은 일시적으로 그룹으로 이동됩니다.
We have no chance to work together now
지금은 같이 일할 기회가 없어
This is actually better
사실 이게 더 나은데
I also need time to fill my broken heart
나에게도 상처받은 마음을 채울 시간이 필요해
Why did you confess to him in the tea room?
왜 찻집에서 그에게 고백을 한 걸까요?
That is to say
즉 말하자면
If I drink, I can still pretend not to remember
술 마시면 아직도 기억 못하는 척 할 수 있어
But this time I really can't argue
하지만 이번엔 정말 반박할 수 없어
Damn it
젠장
Hey, I'm done
이봐, 난 끝났어
Xiaomin seems to have also joined the task force
샤오민도 태스크 포스에 합류한 것 같습니다
Alas, my mentor always shines
아아, 내 멘토는 언제나 빛난다
Why did you suddenly bring this up?
갑자기 이 얘기는 왜 꺼낸 걸까요?
Yes, Minister, itinerary...
네, 장관님, 일정표...
Sorry, I have something urgent to deal with
미안, 급하게 처리할 일이 있어
sorry
죄송합니다
I think he's about to hit you
내 생각엔 그 사람이 곧 당신을 때릴 것 같아
good
좋은
Thanks
감사해요
correct
옳은
Xiaomin said that the person he likes is the chief public relations officer of your company
샤오민이 좋아하는 사람 이 회사 홍보담당자라고 하더군요
Is that a very high position?
아주 높은 지위인가요?
Anyway, she's the woman from San Diego
어쨌든 그 사람은 샌디에고 출신 여자야
Subtitle translation: Zhang Xinru
자막 번역: 장신루(Zhang Xinru)